# JOSH GILLESPIE



I AM A STRIVING WEB DEVELOPER, TECHNOLOGY ENTHUSIAST, HUSBAND, NATURE LOVER, AND AVID GAMER. I'VE RECENTLY TRANSITIONED FROM LIVE, LARGE SCALE AUDIO, LIGHTING, AND STAGE PRODUCTION, TO PURSUE CODING AND WEB DEVELOPMENT. THE BLEND OF PROBLEM SOLVING AND CREATIVITY REQUIRED TO BUILD ANY NEW APPLICATION GREATLY CHALLENGING AND REWARDING. I ENJOY BOTH FRONT END AND BACK END DESIGN AS BOTH BRING THEIR OWN UNIQUE HURDLES AND OPPORTUNITIES.

#### Just A Little Bit About Me

Technology has always been my passion, and it is my firm belief that its purpose is to enhance our lives in the modern age. I started volunteering with my church's tech team when I was 12 years old, learning little by little about using audio and video equipment. I immediately loved having the ability to be creative using technology. Eventually I became production director at that same church, overseeing the live production of all weekend services. In college, I studied business management, but recently decided that I would like to pursue web and App. development. I attended Coding Dojo in Seattle where I was able to solidify my coding foundation. They teach students how to build responsive front end designs using HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery as well as how to build fast, functional, efficient back ends using PHP, Node.js, and Ruby. We also became familiar with multiple MVC frameworks such as Codeigniter, Express.js, and Rails. I will always enjoy learning new technologies, languages, and frameworks and look forward to continuing to advance my skill set in the future.

### Skills / Technical Experience

HTML/CSS & HTML5/CSS3	Ruby on Rails
JavaScript / jQuery / Node.js	Bootstrap
PHP / Codeigniter	UI / UX
Version Control	Adobe Suite
MySQL	Social Media

# Professional Experience

### Production Director / Church by the Glades

August 2011 - August 2013

Responsible for technical requirements, including audio, lighting, and stage design for seven services accross three venues with 6000+ people attending weekly.

Managed 2 employees and over 50 volunteers, including recruitment and continuous training for new and existing volunteers.

A member of the creative team responsible for developing and executing new & unique ideas on a weekly basis.

Required to meet strict deadlines and work under high pressure in a live environment.

Video Assistant / Church by the Glades

October 2010 - August 2011

Experience using professional video equipment, including Sony and RED cameras.

Edited weekly videos using Final Cut Pro and directed live, weekly services at satellite campus.

Responsible for contacting, scheduling, and training new volunteers.

Acted as producer and lighting director for all live youth services.

#### Education

Web Development / Coding Dojo

January 2014 - April 2014

Bachelors in Business Management / Florida Atlantic University

August 2006 - December 2010

Continuing Education / Various Sources

Ongoing

- > Lynda.com and Skill Share video classes
- > CodeAcademy.com; JavaScript and jQuery
- > Various online resources; CSS3, HTML5, jQuery, Responsive Design

## Strengths

Ambitious and motivated individual with many talents to offer

- > Enjoys building apps and websites from design comps
- > Works great under pressure and with deadlines
- > Willing to learn new things
- > Always willing to hear constructive criticism and accept responsibility for mistakes
- > Fun and outgoing personality